Jason Peñalosa

Metro Manila, National Capital Region, Philippines



penalosajason@gmail.com



9957994194



linkedin.com/in/jason-pe%C3%B1alosa-280808120

Summary

Data Analytics Practitioner with in-depth experienced in SQL Server scripting, Report Visualization, ERP, SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, Business Intelligence, Tableau, Power BI, and many other reporting tools. Knowledgeable in VB scripting, Visual C#, Basic Python and web development. Data science enthusiast, a good team player with sense of responsibility and urgency. Certified in ITIL 4 professional and Lean Six Sigma Yellow belt Courses. With vocational courses in HTML 5 and Electronics. With more than 6 years of overall working experienced in the field of Business Intelligence and Data Analytics.

Experience



Microsoft Analytics Lead (Power BI Consultant)

IBM

Dec 2020 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

Lead team of Data Analysts deployed to different projects to monitor the current status of their projects and workloads.

Interview newly hired Power BI specialist to be deployed in a project within IBM, PMI Account. Also deployed in a project containing Data Scientists, Data Engineers, and Data Architects to support companies' innovation projects and enhancement through data science and analytics.

Create insightful dashboards and reports to be used for company-wide analysis and forecasting. Use snowflake, Hadoop, SQL Server, Jupyter as data sources for the data dashboard.

Provide analysis with the data before it will be used in power bi dashboard.



Senior Business Intelligence Engineer

Infor

2020 - Dec 2020 (1 year)

Business Intelligence Analyst

Reports Developer

- As a Report Developer, my main role is to develop reports requested by business.
- We do long term and short term projects and daily support to our internal users.
- Communicates with on-shore partners to provide high-quality reports to our users.
- Follows Business Requirements indicated in the Business Requirements Document.
- Strictly follows SDLC process in project management.

SQL Server Developer

- As part of my role being a BI Engineer, I am also assigned to create / update scripts as main source of our reporting tools.
- Analyze items from TDD to create datasets for our reports.

Cognos Reports Developer

-IBM Cognos reports SME.

Infor Query and Analys Developer (Internal tool)

- Main contact for any Q&A inquiries and development.
- In-depth integration with MS Excel and SQL Server and macro scripting
- Uses TFS as a repository tool and version control tool

Infor Business Intelligence Analytics Tool (Internal tool

- Manage and maintain IBI reporting tool to provide reports to users.
- in-depth integration with jobs and cubes processes.

Power BI Developer

- Maintain and create reports for business users using Power BI.
- in depth integration with API, sharepoint etc.

infor Business Intelligence Engineer Associate

Infor

Dec 2018 - Dec 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Associate Business Intelligence Engineer

Reports Developer

- As a Report Developer, my main role is to develop reports requested by business.
- We do long term and short term projects and daily support to our internal users.
- Communicates with on-shore partners to provide high-quality reports to our users.
- Follows Business Requirements indicated in the Business Requirements Document.
- Strictly follows SDLC process in project management.

SQL Server Developer

- As part of my role being a BI Engineer, I am also assigned to create / update scripts as main source of our reporting tools.
- Analyze items from TDD to create datasets for our reports.

Cognos Reports Developer

- I am also a resource in maintaining and managing our Cognos reports.

Infor Query and Analys Developer (Internal tool)

- Main contact for any Q&A inquiries and development.
- In-depth integration with MS Excel and SQL Server and macro scripting
- Uses TFS as a repository tool and version control tool

Infor Business Intelligence Analytics Tool (Internal tool)

- Manage and maintain IBI reporting tool to provide reports to users.
- in-depth integration with jobs and cubes processes.

Power BI Developer

- Maintain and create reports for business users using Power BI.
- in depth integration with API, sharepoint etc.

Software Engineer

Accenture

Jan 2018 - Nov 2018 (11 months)

Software Engineer || Business Intelligence Engineer

Designated Project: Scan Health Plan

SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) Developer

- As an SSRS Developer, my main role is to develop reports requested by business.
- We do long term and short term projects and daily support to our users.
- Communicates with on-shore partners to provide high-quality reports to our users.
- Follows Business Requirements indicated in the Business Requirements Document.
- Converts BRD to Technical Desgin Document (TDD)
- Strictly follows SDLC process in project management.

SQL Server Developer

- As part of my role being a BI Engineer, I am also assigned to create / update scripts as main source of our reporting tools.
- Analyze items from TDD to create datasets for our reports.

SSIS Developer

- Being a BI Engineer, we also monitor jobs and create packages to transform data from raw sources.

End to End developer

- From project creation, extracting, transforming and loading data to analyzing, creating data set, developing reports and supporting the reports.
- Uses TFS as a repository tool and version control tool

Associate Software Engineer

Accenture

Nov 2016 - Dec 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Associate Software Engineer || Business Intelligence Engineer

Designated Project: Scan Health Plan

SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) Developer

- As an SSRS Developer, my main role is to develop reports requested by business.
- We do long term and short term projects and daily support to our users.
- Communicates with on-shore partners to provide high-quality reports to our users.
- Follows Business Requirements indicated in the Business Requirements Document.
- Converts BRD to Technical Desgin Document (TDD)
- Strictly follows SDLC process in project management.

SQL Server Developer

- As part of my role being a BI Engineer, I am also assigned to create / update scripts as main source of our reporting tools.
- Analyze items from TDD to create datasets for our reports.

SSIS Developer

- Being a BI Engineer, we also monitor jobs and create packages to transform data from raw sources.

End to End developer

- From project creation, extracting, transforming and loading data to analyzing, creating data set, developing reports and supporting the reports.
- Uses TFS as a repository tool and version control tool

Solutions Specialist

ServiceIT+ Inc.

Mar 2016 - Jul 2016 (5 months)

As a solution specialist, we were trained to provide support to our clients thru ticketing system. I am on the tech department where I handle most of the scripting issue and technical problems within the application we support. We do weekly training to upgrade our skills in the fields of web development and presentation. I was also assigned as one of the developers of the company's website.

Education



Master of Science in Innovation and Business 2021 - 2022

😭 Polytechnic University of the Philippines

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology 2012 - 2016

ACLC College

Vocational Course, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources Design 2011 - 2012

Licenses & Certifications

Certified Data Analyst - Trained - Ask Lex PH Academy

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification - ProcessDoctorsAcademy LSSYB-1594571096-2001-2044

9980032610726453

ITIL® 4 Foundation CPD - AXELOS Global Best Practice Issued Oct 2020 - Expires Sep 2021

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner - IBM

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals - Microsoft

Skills

Business Intelligence • ITIL Certified • Big Data Analytics • Business Intelligence (BI) • Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) • Business Strategy • Entrepreneurship • Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) • IBM Cognos Analytics • Microsoft Power BI

Honors & Awards

Service Excellence Award - IBM

Apr 2021

Data Analytics Practitioner of the year - Ask Lex PH Academy

Dec 2021

Recognized as Data Analytics Practioner of the Year by AskLex PH Academy